config: 
  integrationBranch: "integration"
  deployCommand: "rake $environment$ deploy[$tag$]"
tests:
  name: "Root"
  tests:
    - name: "No CI tag"
      spec:
        input:
          prompts:
            - question: "Choose your adventure: Start new release (0), Start hotfix (1)"
              answer: "0"
        output:
          commands:
            - "git tags"
            - "git branch"
          stderr: 
            - "Program Error: Could not find latest green tag"

    - name: "CI tag exists"
      spec:
        input:
          tags:
            - "ci/123\n"

      tests:
        - name: "No release in progress"
          spec:
            input:
              tags:
                - "release/1.2.3\n"
                - "release/1.2.3-rc3\n"
          tests:
            - name: "Start a new release"
              spec:
                input:
                  prompts:
                    - question: "Choose your adventure: Start new release (0), Start hotfix (1)"
                      answer: "0"
                output:
                  commands:
                    - "git tags"
                    - "git branch"
                    - "git checkout ci/123"
                    - "git tag release/1.3.0-rc1"
                    - "git push origin --tags"
                  stdout: 
                    - "Started new release: release/1.3.0-rc1, deploy to preproduction and confirm the release is good to go!"
                    - "Deploy to preproduction and confirm the release is good to go!"
                    - "rake preproduction deploy[release/1.3.0]"


            - name: "Start a hotfix"
              spec:
                input:
                  prompts:
                    - question: "Choose your adventure: Start new release (0), Start hotfix (1)"
                      answer: "1"
                    - question: "What is the hotfix for? (specify dash separated descriptor, e.g. 'signup-is-broken')"
                      answer: "hot-fixing"
                output:
                  commands:
                    - "git tags"
                    - "git branch"
                    - "git checkout release/1.2.3"
                    - "git checkout -b release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                  stdout: 
                    - "Started hotfix: release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing, fix stuff!"

      tests:
        - name: "Hotfix in progress"
          spec:
            input:
              tags:
                - "release/1.2.3\n"
              branches:
                - "release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
          tests:
            - name: "Not yet completed"
              spec:
                input:
                  prompts:
                    - question: "Is the hotfix complete? y(es)/n(o)"
                      answer: "n"
                output:
                  commands:
                    - "git tags"
                    - "git branch"
                    - "git checkout release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                  stdout:
                    - "Hotfix found: release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                    - "Keep fixing that code!"

            - name: "Completed"
              spec:
                input:
                  prompts:
                    - question: "Is the hotfix complete? y(es)/n(o)"
                      answer: "y"
                output:
                  commands:
                    - "git tags"
                    - "git branch"
                    - "git checkout release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                    - "git tag release/1.2.4-rc1"
                    - "git push origin --tags"
                    - "git checkout release/1.2.4-rc1"
                    - "git branch -d release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                    - "git push origin :release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                  stdout:
                    - "Hotfix found: release/1.2.3/hotfix/hot-fixing"
                    - "Started new release: release/1.2.4-rc1, deploy to preproduction and confirm the release is good to go!"

      tests:
        - name: "Release is in progress"
          spec:
            input:
              tags:
                - "release/1.2.3\n"
          tests:
            - name: "Release candidate is GOOD"
              spec:
                input:
                  prompts:
                    - question: "Is this release candidate good? y(es)/n(o)"
                      answer: "y"
              tests:
                - name: "Minor version bump"
                  spec:
                    input:
                      tags:
                        - "release/1.3.0-rc1\n"
                        - "release/1.3.0-rc2\n"
                    output:
                      commands:
                        - "git tags"
                        - "git branch"
                        - "git checkout release/1.3.0-rc2"
                        - "git tag release/1.3.0"
                        - "git push origin --tags"
                        - "git checkout release/1.3.0"
                      stdout:
                        - "Release candidate found: release/1.3.0-rc2"
                        - "Created tag: release/1.3.0" 
                        - "Deploy to production cowboy!"
                        - "rake production deploy[release/1.3.0]"

                - name: "Patch version bump (hotfix)"
                  spec:
                    input:
                      tags:
                        - "release/1.2.4-rc1\n"
                        - "release/1.2.4-rc2\n"
                    output:
                      commands:
                        - "git tags"
                        - "git branch"
                        - "git checkout release/1.2.4-rc2"
                        - "git tag release/1.2.4"
                        - "git push origin --tags"
                        - "git checkout integration"
                        - "git pull --rebase"
                        - "git merge --no-ff release/1.2.4"
                        - "git push origin integration"
                        - "git checkout release/1.2.4"
                      stdout:
                        - "Release candidate found: release/1.2.4-rc2"
                        - "Created tag: release/1.2.4"
                        - "Deploy to production cowboy!"
                        - "rake production deploy[release/1.2.4]"


            - name: "Release candidate is BAD, initiate bug fix"
              spec:
                input:
                  prompts:
                    - question: "Is this release candidate good? y(es)/n(o)"
                      answer: "n"
                    - question: "What bug are you fixing? (specify dash separated descriptor, e.g. 'theres-a-bug-in-the-code')"
                      answer: "theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                  tags:
                    - "release/1.3.0-rc1\n"
                    - "release/1.3.0-rc2\n"
                output:
                  commands:
                    - "git tags"
                    - "git branch"
                    - "git checkout release/1.3.0-rc2"
                    - "git checkout -b release/1.3.0-rc2/tmp"
                    - "git checkout -b release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                  stdout: 
                    - "Release candidate found: release/1.3.0-rc2"
                    - "Created branch: release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code, fix your bug!"


            - name: "Release candidate was BAD, bug fix was in progress"
              spec:
                input:
                  branches:
                    - "release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                  tags:
                    - "release/1.3.0-rc1\n"
                    - "release/1.3.0-rc2\n"
              tests:
                - name: "Bug fix complete"
                  spec:
                    input:
                      prompts:
                        - question: "Is the bug fixed? y(es)/n(o)"
                          answer: "y"
                    output:
                      commands:
                        - "git tags"
                        - "git branch"
                        - "git checkout release/1.3.0-rc2/tmp"
                        - "git merge --no-ff release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                        - "git checkout integration"
                        - "git pull --rebase"
                        - "git merge --no-ff release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                        - "git push origin integration"
                        - "git checkout release/1.3.0-rc2/tmp"
                        - "git branch -d release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                        - "git push origin :release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                        - "git tag release/1.3.0-rc3"
                        - "git push origin --tags"
                        - "git checkout release/1.3.0-rc3"
                        - "git branch -d release/1.3.0-rc2/tmp"
                        - "git push origin :release/1.3.0-rc2/tmp"
                      stdout:
                        - "Bugfix found: release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                        - "Created new release candidate: release/1.3.0-rc3, you'll get it this time!"

                - name: "Bug fix not complete"
                  spec:
                    input:
                      prompts:
                        - question: "Is the bug fixed? y(es)/n(o)"
                          answer: "n"

                    output:
                      commands:
                        - "git tags"
                        - "git branch"
                        - "git checkout release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                      stdout: 
                        - "Bugfix found: release/1.3.0-rc2/bugs/theres-a-bug-in-the-code"
                        - "Keep fixing that code!"


